A Guide to the Asian Cultural Council records, Conferences, Festivals and Seminars, RG 2 FA1400
Rockefeller Archive Center
Asian Cultural Council records, Conferences, Festivals and Seminars, RG 2
1963-1992
Rockefeller Archive Center
Asian Cultural Council
FA1400
13.64 Cubic Feet 29 letter document boxes, 2 standard record storage boxes, Boxes 249-277, Box 408, 409.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Record Group 2 is arranged in three series:
Series 1: Conferences and Seminars
Series 2: Festivals
Series 3: Workshop
Biographical / Historical
The Asian Cultural Council is a publicly supported not for profit 501(c)(3) established in 1980 to support cultural exchange between Asia and the United States. The Council carries forward the mission of the Asian Cultural Program of the JDR 3rd Fund, which had been created by JDR 3rd in 1963 and was officially dissolved in July 1979.
The Asian Cultural Council maintains offices in New York, Hong Kong, Manila (Philippines), Taipei (Taiwan) and Tokyo. ACC affiliation with the Rockefeller Brothers Fund began in 1991, enabling the Council to reduce administrative overhead and devote a larger percentage of its funds directly to grants and program development.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Asian Cultural Council records were donated to the RAC in 2010.
Scope and Contents
Record Group 2 documents conference and seminar planning, conference participants and papers, primarily spanning the 1970s and 1980s. Also represented are a variety of festival files focusing primarily on the Festival of India in the 1980s.
- Conferences, Festivals and Seminars, 1963-1992; 2
  - Conferences and Seminars, 1963-1985; 1
    - College Art Association of America, Washington D. C., 1979 (Box 249, Folder 1)
    - American Theatre Association, CF, New Orleans, 1978 (Box 249, Folder 2)
    - College Art Association, Annual Meeting, New York, NY, 1978 January 25 (Box 249, Folder 3)
    - American Association of Museums, Seattle, Washington, 1977 May 29-June 2 (Box 249, Folder 4)
    - American Theatre Association, Chicago, Conference, 1977 August 14-17 (Box 249, Folder 5)
    - Association for Asian Studies, New York, 1977 March 25-27 (Box 249, Folder 6)
    - College Art Association of America, Los Angeles, 1977 February 2-5 (Box 249, Folder 7)
    - Yale University, Symposium on Chinese Calligraphy, New Haven, CT, 1977 April 8-10 (Box 249, Folder 8)
    - American Association of Museums, USCF, Annual Meeting in Washington D. C., 1976 May 30-June 3 (Box 249, Folder 9)
    - Association for Asian Studies, Annual Meeting, 1976 March 19-21 (Box 249, Folder 10)
    - International Musicological Society, Berkeley, CA, 1977 August (Box 250, Folder 1)
    - East-West Center Conference, Honolulu, 1976 December 9-10 (Box 250, Folder 2)
    - International Council of Museums (ICOM) Conference, Moscow, 1977 (Box 250, Folder 3)
    - American Association of Museums (AAM), 1965-1983 (Box 251, Folder 1)
    - American Institute of Indian Studies, 1966-1975 (Box 251, Folder 2)
    - Agricultural Development Council, US Organization, Abraham Weisblat (Box 251, Folder 3)
    - Agricultural Development Council, US Organization, General Correspondence (Box 251, Folder 4)
    - Alaska Festival of Music, US Organization (Box 251, Folder 5)
    - Sixth United States-Japan Conference on Cultural and Education Interchange (CULCON), 1972 (Box 252, Folder 1)
    - Hazen Foundation, Smithsonian Institution, 1973 January (Box 252, Folder 2)
    - American Association of Museums, Mexico, 1972 June (Box 252, Folder 3)
    - Association for Asian Studies, 24th Meeting, New York, 1972 March (Box 252, Folder 4)
    - ASPAC - Conference on Cooperation Among the Museums in the Asian and Pacific Region, Tokyo, 1972 November (Box 252, Folder 5)
    - National Gallery of Art, D. C., Conference on Museum Training Programs, Washington D. C., 1972 December (Box 252, Folder 6)
    - Asia Pacific Conference on Conservation of Cultural Property, Nation Museum, New Delhi, 1972 February 7-12 (Box 252, Folder 7)
    - Seminar on Southeast Asian Prehistory and Archaeology, National Museum, Philippines, 1972 June 26-July 3 (Box 253, Folder 1)
    - New York Conference on Asian Studies (Box 253, Folder 2)
    - UNESCO-ICOM, Malaysia, Malacca, 1972 December (Box 253, Folder 3)
    - ICOM, Ninth General Conference, Paris and Grenoble, 1971 (Box 254, Folder 1)
    - ICOM, Ninth General Conference, Paris and Grenoble, 1971 (Box 254, Folder 2)
    - American Association of Museums, New York, 1970 May 31-June 4 (Box 254, Folder 3)
    - Association for Asian Studies, 22nd Annual Meeting, San Francisco, 1970 April (Box 254, Folder 4)
    - Institute of International Education, The Arts: An International Force, New York, 1970 April-May (Box 254, Folder 5)
    - International Design Conference in Aspen, Aspen, 1970 June 14-19 (Box 254, Folder 6)
    - Aspen Design Conference, Aspen, 1969 June 15-20 (Box 254, Folder 7)
    - American Theatre Association, Conference, New York, 1979 August 12-15 (Box 255, Folder 1)
    - Association for Asian Studies, Los Angeles, 1979 March 30-April 1 (Box 255, Folder 2)
    - Society for Ethnomusicology, Conferences, Montreal, 1979 October (Box 255, Folder 3)
    - ICOM, Mexico, 1980 October 25-November 4 (Box 255, Folder 4)
    - Society for Ethnomusicology Conference, Bloomington, Indiana, 1980 November 20-23 (Box 255, Folder 5)
    - New England Conference for the Association for Asian Studies, 1980 October (Box 255, Folder 6)
    - College Art Association, USCF, New Orleans, 1980 (Box 255, Folder 7)
    - CISP Funding Seminar, Washington D. C. (Council for Intercultural Studies and Programs), 1980 March 20 (Box 255, Folder 8)
    - World Property Conference, UNIMA XIII, Washington D. C. (Union Internationale de la Marionnette), 1980 June 8 (Box 255, Folder 9)
    - ASPAC, Museum Conference, Taipei, 1974 March (Box 256, Folder 1)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, Toronto, 1974 October (Box 256, Folder 2)
    - Association for Asian Studies, Boston, 1974 April (Box 256, Folder 3)
    - College Art Association, 62nd Annual Meeting, Detroit, 1974 January (Box 256, Folder 4)
    - International Council of Museums, 10th General Conference, Copenhagen, 1974 June (Box 256, Folder 5)
    - ICOM, Modern Art Committee, New York, 1974 April (Box 256, Folder 6)
    - Japan Society, Role of Foundations in the US-Japan Relations, NY, 1974 May (Box 256, Folder 7)
    - Asia House Gallery, Correspondence, US Organization, Kay Bergl, 1973-1979 (Box 256, Folder 8)
    - Asia Society, Performing Arts Program, Correspondence, Isadora Bennett (Box 257, Folder 1)
    - International Association of Art, 6th Congress, Amsterdam, 1969 October 6-11 (Box 257, Folder 2)
    - College Art Association of America, Society of Architectural Historians, Washington, D. C., 1968 January 29-February 1 (Box 257, Folder 3)
    - ICOM - Eight General Conference, Cologne and Munich, 1968 July-August (Box 257, Folder 4)
    - Brown University, USEI, "Work", PRM (Box 277)
    - Council on Foundations, Chicago, 1975 April (Box 258, Folder 1)
    - Society for Ethnomusicology Conference, Philadelphia, 1976 November 10-14 (Box 258, Folder 2)
    - Japan Center for the International Exchange, Tokyo, 1975 January (Box 258, Folder 3)
    - National Committee on US-China Relations, 1975 October (Box 258, Folder 3)
    - Japan Center for the International Exchange, Tokyo, 1975 January (Box 258, Folder 4)
    - Society for Ethnomusicology Conference, Wesleyan, Middletown, 1975 October (Box 258, Folder 5)
    - NY State Council on the Arts, Whitney Museum, NY, Fundraising, 1974 April (Box 258, Folder 6)
    - American Association of Museums, Milwaukee, 1973 June (Box 258, Folder 7)
    - New York Conference on Asian Studies, New Paltz, 1973 November (Box 258, Folder 8)
    - Society for Architectural Historians, New Orleans, 1974 April (Box 258, Folder 9)
    - Temple University, Conference on Visual Anthropology, Philadelphia, 1974 March (Box 258, Folder 10)
    - College Art Association of America, 61st Meeting, NYC, 1973 January (Box 258, Folder 11)
    - Ameriasian Seminar, Lamore, 1965 February (Box 258, Folder 12)
    - Council on Foundations, 20th Annual meeting, New Orleans, 1967 April 9-11 (Box 258, Folder 13)
    - American Theatre Association, 37th Annual Meeting, NY, 1973 August (Box 258, Folder 14)
    - American Craftsmen?s Council, First Congress, New York, 1964 June (Box 259, Folder 1)
    - ICOM, Symposium on Museum Architecture, Mexico City, 1968 December 8-14 (Box 259, Folder 2)
    - New York University, The 8th Biennial Conference on Charitable Foundations, New York, 1967 May 15-16 (Box 259, Folder 3)
    - College Art Association, USCF, San Francisco, 1981 (Box 259, Folder 4)
    - Association for Asian Studies, Washington, D. C., 1980 March 21-23 (Box 259, Folder 5)
    - Japan Society, Culcon Symposium, Conference, 1976 May 22-26 (Box 259, Folder 6)
    - American Association of Museums, Los Angeles, 1975 June (Box 259, Folder 7)
    - US Conferences, N-Z, 1969-1973 (Box 259, Folder 8)
    - US Conference, A-M, 1964-1981 (Box 260, Folder 1)
    - US Conference, General, 1981 (Box 260, Folder 2)
    - 26th Conference of the International Folk Music Council, Seoul, 1981 August (Box 260, Folder 3)
    - International Congress of Orientalists, Internation Congress of Human Science in Asia and North Africa, Conference, 1976 (Box 260, Folder 4)
    - Japan Society, Symposium, Shinto History and Aesthetics, NYC, 1976 September-October (Box 260, Folder 5)
    - Second US-Japan Conference on Education and Cultural Exchange (CULCON), 1963 (Box 260, Folder 6)
    - Law and Social Change Seminar, Transcript, 1985 (Box 261, Folder 1)
    - Law and Social Change, Meagher Trip to India, 1980 July (Box 261, Folder 2)
    - Law and Social Change Seminar, 1981 November 30-December 2 (Box 261, Folder 3)
    - Visitorship, General, 1980-1981 (Box 261, Folder 4)
    - Visitorship Program, Shafi, Sayed, 1982 (Box 261, Folder 5)
    - Visitorship, Nandy, Ashis, 1979-1980 (Box 261, Folder 6)
    - Visitorship, Sandhu, G. S., 1979-1980 (Box 261, Folder 7)
    - Visitorship Program, Black, Max (Box 261, Folder 8)
    - Visitorship Program, 1982 (Box 261, Folder 9)
    - Catlin, Amy (Box 261, Folder 10)
    - Visitorship, Name Request, Gutman (Box 261, Folder 11)
    - Visitorship, Mandelbaum, David (Box 261, Folder 12)
    - Visitorship Program, Sen, Paritosh, 1981 (Box 262, Folder 1)
    - Visitorship Program, Narain, Hari, 1981 (Box 262, Folder 2)
    - Visitorship Program, Anansalakshmi, 1981 (Box 262, Folder 3)
    - Visitorship Program, Thapar, B. K., 1981 (Box 262, Folder 4)
    - Visitorship, Shannon, Bayley, Lapalombara, Gunther to India, 1979-1980 (Box 262, Folder 5)
    - Visitorship, Sethi, Rajeev, 1979 October (Box 262, Folder 6)
    - Visitorship, General, 1980 (Box 262, Folder 7)
    - Visitorship, General, Indians to US, Tilak, 1980 (Box 262, Folder 8)
    - Visitoship Program, Secretariat, 1977-1978 (Box 262, Folder 9)
    - Visitoship Program, Butler, George (Box 262, Folder 10)
    - Visitorship Program, Turner, Victor (Box 262, Folder 11)
    - Law and Social Change, PPS (Box 262, Folder 12)
    - Visitorship Program, 1983 (Box 262, Folder 13)
    - Law and Social Change Project, 1979 September 24 (Box 263, Folder 1)
    - Meeting, Joint Seminar, Legal, Norberg, Charles (Box 263, Folder 2)
    - Journalists Roundtable, University of Penn, 1980 (Box 263, Folder 3)
    - SC, Proposed Joint Activity of Science and Technology (Box 263, Folder 4)
    - Effects of Deprivation Seminar, 1980 May (Box 263, Folder 5)
    - Effects of Deprivation Seminar, Follow-up Activities (Box 263, Folder 6)
    - Effects of Deprivation Seminar, Preliminary Meetings, Trips, Info (Box 263, Folder 7)
    - Sub-Commission: Education Technology, Evaluation of Radio and TV Instructional Materials (Box 263, Folder 8)
    - Sub-Commission: "Education Technology" Seminar, Computers in Education, 1976 (Box 264, Folder 1)
    - Sub-Commission: Joint Seminar, University Research and National Development (Box 264, Folder 2)
    - University Research and Development Seminar, Follow-up (Box 264, Folder 3)
    - Sub-Commission, ?Museums as Educational Resource, Joint Seminar, 1975 (Box 264, Folder 4)
    - Joint Seminar, University Research and National Development, 1978 (Box 264, Folder 5)
    - Seminar, Educational Technology, Mitra, Shib, NCERT (Box 264, Folder 6)
    - Preparation of Instructional Mt?l, 1978-1979 (Box 264, Folder 7)
    - Joint Seminar - Research and Development, Logisitcs, 1978 September 18-22 (Box 264, Folder 8)
    - Sub-Commission, Joint Seminars, Seminar in Indian Music, Dance and Drama (Box 264, Folder 9)
    - SSRC-Compensatory Programs, Seminar, Inactive (Box 264, Folder 10)
    - Proposed Joint Seminar, Nutrition and Education (Box 264, Folder 11)
    - Schweitzer, Indo-US Seminar on Role of Universities in Technology Assessment, 1978 (Box 264, Folder 12)
    - Joint Seminar, Museums as Educational Resource, 1976 April (Box 264, Folder 13)
    - Seminar, Linkages of Agriculture and Education (LAE)-American Papers (Box 265, Folder 1)
    - Sub-Commission, LAE (Box 265, Folder 2)
    - Sub-Commission, LAE, Seminar, Bouton Trip, Rockefeller Foundation Grant (Box 265, Folder 3)
    - LAE, Follow-up and Proposal for Working Group (Box 265, Folder 4)
    - Sub-Commission, Joint Seminar, Linkages of Agriculture and Education Proceedings (Box 265, Folder 5)
    - LAE American Papers, Revised Versions (Box 265, Folder 6)
    - Sub-Commission, LAE, Travel (Box 265, Folder 7)
    - Linkages of Agriculture and Education (Box 265, Folder 8)
    - Law and Social Changes Seminar, Papers and Participants, 1983 (Box 265, Folder 9)
    - Law and Social Change, Working Papers, 1983 June 13-15 (Box 266, Folder 1)
    - Wenner-Gran International Symposium, Theater Conference Papers, 1982 (Box 266, Folder 2)
  - Festivals, 1981-1990; 2
    - International Dance Film and Videotape Festival, Library and Museum of Performing Arts, Lincoln Center, NY, 1981 June 15-19 (Box 266, Folder 3)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - American Press, 1982 July-1985 March (Box 266, Folder 4)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - American Press, 1985 April-June (Box 267, Folder 1-4)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - American Press, 1985 July-September (Box 268, Folder 1-5)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - American Press, 1985 September-November (Box 269, Folder 1-5)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - American Press, 1985 December-1986 March (Box 270, Folder 1-4)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - American Press, 1986 April-1987 December (Box 271, Folder 1-9)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Files, 1985 December (Box 271, Folder 10-11)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Files, 1985 November (Box 272, Folder 1-3)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - India - General (Box 272, Folder 1-4)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Clippings - Ethnic Press, 1983-1986 (Box 273, Folder 1-5)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Selection of Newsclippings from US, French an Indian Press, 1985 June-October (Box 277)
    - Earth Rites, Photographs from Inside the Third World, Solomon, Rosalind, Exhibition Catalog of the Museum of Photographic Arts, 1986 April 8-June 1 (Box 277)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Calendar Meetings, 1985-1986 (Box 273, Folder 6)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Magazines, Pamphlets, Booklets, 1985-1990 (Box 274, Folder 1-7)
    - Festival of India (FOI), 1981-1986 (Box 275, Folder 1)
    - Festival of India (FOI) (Box 275, Folder 2)
    - New York Public Library, "The World of Jainism" and Other Exhibitions (Box 275, Folder 3)
    - Museum of Science and Industry, "Science and Technology: The Indian Tradition" (Box 275, Folder 4)
    - Golden Eye (Box 275, Folder 5)
    - Contemporary Theater, "Ghashiram Kotwal" (Box 275, Folder 6)
    - Asian Art Museum, San Francisco, "The Essence of Indian Art" (Box 275, Folder 7)
    - Reciprocal Loan From Philadelphia Museum of Art to National Museum, Delhi (Box 275, Folder 8)
    - The World of Gandhi and Nehru (Box 275, Folder 9)
    - UCLA, Frederick S. Wright Art Gallery, "Visions of Inner Space" (Box 275, Folder 10)
    - Allegations of Damage to Objects Lent for Festival of India (Box 275, Folder 11)
    - Exhibition of Indian Textiles, Visvakarma (Box 275, Folder 12)
    - Brooklyn Museum Terracotta Exhibit, A180 (Box 276, Folder 1)
    - The Jewish Museum (Box 276, Folder 2)
    - Metropolitan, Costume Institute, Indian Court Costumes (Box 276, Folder 3)
    - American Museum of National History, "Vijayanagra: Where Kings and Gods Meet" (Box 276, Folder 4)
    - American Museum of National History, "Tiger, Tiger Burning Bright" (Box 276, Folder 5)
    - Smithsonian Institution, "Aditi: A Celebration of Life" (Box 276, Folder 6)
    - Dartmouth College, Asian Studies Program (Box 276, Folder 7)
    - Dixon Gallery and Gardens, "Art of India: Miniature Painting" (Box 276, Folder 8)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, "The Pursuit of Power and Pleasure: Secular Tradition in Indian Painting" (Box 276, Folder 9)
    - "American Understanding of India", Library of Congress, 1986 October (Box 276, Folder 10)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Calendar of Events (Box 276, Folder 11)
    - Festival of India (FOI) - Miscellaneous Affiliated Events (Box 276, Folder 12)
  - Workshops, 1978-1992; 3
    - Conservation, Summary Record (Box 408, Folder 1)
    - Sub-Commission: Joint Seminar on Conservation, Papers (Box 408, Folder 2)
    - Conservation Seminar Dinner, Reception, 1978 June 12-13 (Box 408, Folder 3)
    - Conservation on Paper Material Seminar, 1978 (Box 408, Folder 4)
    - Conservation Workshop, Wall Paintings, 1980 April 2-7 (Box 408, Folder 5)
    - Conservation Workshop III, Effects on Air Pollution on Cultural Properties, 1982 (Box 408, Folder 6)
    - Conservation Workshop IV - Conservation Stone, 1984 January (Box 408, Folder 7)
    - Conservation Workshop V, Conservation of Metal, 1985 (Box 408, Folder 8)
    - Conservation, Oil Painting, New Delhi, 1986 January (Box 408, Folder 9)
    - Conservation Workshop on Bioderioration of Cultural Materials, 1987 May 23-June 1 (Box 408, Folder 10)
    - Conservation Workshop, Indian Miniature Paintings, 1988 January 24-31 (Box 408, Folder 11)
    - Conservation Workshop 9, USA, Display and Storage of Textiles, 1989 May (Box 408, Folder 12)
    - Sihari-Baer, Conservation Center, National Museum-Institute of Fine Arts, 1989-1990 (Box 409, Folder 1)
    - Conservation Workshop, "Training" in India, 1990 (Box 409, Folder 2)
    - Conservation Workshop - Documentation in Conservation, USA, 1991 (Box 409, Folder 3)
    - Conservation Workshop XII, 1992 March 17-22 (Box 409, Folder 4)